GINA KENNEDY: With our busy lifestyles and whatever we do, gravity pulls us down, and so, we end up with rounded shoulders, and a rounded back, and posture that's not exactly where we would want it.
So, the Dandasana pose, staff pose, is one that can counteract the forces of gravity and just life as it presents itself.
So, Faith is going to help me demonstrate Dandasana.
So she's going to extend her legs out in front of her.
Good.
She's going to flex her feet, press through her big toe mound and even spread her toes and pull her toes back towards her knees.
She's going to press her calves right down into the ground.
A, and it's okay if her heels come off just a little bit.
She is going to engage through her thighs.
Good.
She's going to lengthen up, root down with her tailbone and lengthen up through the crown of her head.
Now, Faith has a very nice, long spine.
, But but for some people who've been rounded for a good portion of their life, they're still rounded.
So, I'm going to ask Faith to take these blocks and place them behind her hips, just a little bit, and she's going to press her hands.
So, it might be a little bit too high for you, Faith.
So, we're gonna--you have to experiment to find which is the right spot.